Welcome to Canva.
What I want to show you is how this very powerful online tool, Canva.com, can be used to support the
teaching approach of the activated classroom, which is specifically the pedagogy of chaos.
Now, you might think chaos is a bad thing, but chaos is something that we have to deal with all the
time.
And when we've got too much information or too little information or even conflicting information,
what is important is being able to take all of that information together and put it into something that
brings it succinctly down to a visual representation.
And one of the ways that that is very powerfully done is through what are called infographics.
An infographic is essentially a whole lot of complex information that has been condensed into a visual
representation.
And that's what this pedagogy of chaos is about.
Trying to summarize, really distill the essence of our learning.
And Canva is a great site for doing that.
So if you come across to Canva and choose infographic, you'll be presented with a whole range of templates.
All you now need to do is choose one that you think fits what you want to put together your summary.
So maybe you want to make a series of points so you could choose one like this.
Or you keep going down you'll see this the bulleted one, not as interesting in terms of not being as
graphical, but maybe there are ten things that you want to remember.
What a great way to succinctly bring them all together.
You can get quite visual.
Maybe you want to do it like this.
It shows four items that are key to you and so on and on it goes.
You'll notice that most of them have got free, meaning there's no cost, which is a big plus.
Some of them you do pay for, so just look out for that.
So it's interesting.
All you need to do is choose one which you think, well this would be a great one to to represent my
thinking.
So go down, pick an infographic that you think, well, I'm going to use this one as a visual image
of what I have learned on this particular course.
So I'd say, well, you know, the things I've learned, there's lots of them.
And I wonder what would be a great way for me to represent this.
And again, just by thinking about this for a few minutes, you are having to try and distill your learning
down to something that makes sense.
So let us pick one of these infographics to represent our learning.
Well, this one here looks fun.
We're going to pick it.
Let's play on.
So it's a free infographic.
Quite simply all you need to do is you can zoom in a little bit so you can see it more clearly.
And now you can edit it as simple as that.
You can click on any element and edit your learning.
If you want to change the font or the font size, simply click on it, go to the top and you can change
the font.
You can change colors, you can change all sorts of things.
It really is quite simple and it's now just a matter of putting your content down.
If you want to insert something, an image again, this is also really, really simple.
There are a whole range of elements that can be inserted on the left hand side.
You will see an option to choose what elements you would like to insert.
And so you can search on these.
They can be icons, lines, illustrations, or you could just search over here for whatever the image
you are looking for.
So maybe you are looking for, um, HTML.
Immediately it's going to come up with a whole lot of images.
Again, if they are free, you can use them.
Some you are going to have to pay for.
So maybe I want to use this one here.
So I'll say yes.
That's exactly the one I want.
Click it.
It places it on the page.
You can now resize it and put it wherever you want to get rid of an image.
I don't want that one.
Click it, hit delete and I can put my image here.
Resizing is a simple process.
You can also upload your own images should you want to.
So if you did search for something and you weren't happy with oh, I don't like any of those, you can
go and upload your own image.
But I'm happy with this.
It's free.
It's to do with CSS.
That seems good enough.
Or I could take one of these.
Let's just take this one over here and I will use that.
Right.
So that is essentially the process.
You can continue doing that.
You simply edit each of the items and at the end of it you can produce for yourself a lovely visual
representation of the key things that you learned.
Once you're done, you can quite simply hit download and you can download your image.
You can download it as a PNG, JPEG, or a PDF as simple as that.
And at the end of the day, what you've now created is you've created a lovely, simple infographic
of what you've learned.
It's a great way to distill your learning and to remember it into the day.
You now have an image that summarizes the key points of what you've learned.
So over to you.
Take whatever it is you're learning about.
Get across to Canva and create for yourself a infographic representation of your learning, and you
will have just experienced the power of the activated classroom teaching, pedagogy of chaos and how
it will help you remember your learning.